<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: baduk | Urban Hafner]]></title>
  <link href="http://bettong.net/blog/categories/baduk/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://bettong.net/"/>
  <updated>2015-07-03T08:22:25+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://bettong.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Urban Hafner]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[contact@urbanhafner.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Iomrascálaí: A great way to learn Rust or about AI]]></title>
    <link href="http://bettong.net/2015/01/07/iomrascalai-a-great-way-to-learn-rust-or-about-ai/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-07T09:08:35+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://bettong.net/2015/01/07/iomrascalai-a-great-way-to-learn-rust-or-about-ai</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/rust.png">
I wrote about <a href="https://github.com/ujh/iomrascalai">Iomrascálaí</a>, my
personal project to learn <a href="http://www.rust-lang.org/">Rust</a> by writing
an artificial intelligence for the
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Go_(game)">game of Go</a>,
<a href="/2014/04/29/introducting-iomrascalai/">on here before</a>. Since then
it&rsquo;s gone rather quiet as I haven&rsquo;t had much time to work on it. We
bought a house and moved in, I got a new job, my wife started a new
job, it&rsquo;s winter so the kids get sick all the time &hellip;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Now that things have <em>slightly</em> settled down I&rsquo;m ready to continue
with this project. And this is why I&rsquo;m writing this blog post. If
there&rsquo;s anyone out there who either wants to learn Rust or learn about
artificial intelligence then you&rsquo;re welcome to help out with this
project. I knew nothing about Rust when I started this project, but
that didn&rsquo;t stop <a href="https://github.com/TisButMe">Thomas P</a> from joining
and essentially teaching me Rust. I&rsquo;m very greatful and I&rsquo;d like to
pay it forward by doing the same. So just have a look at the
<a href="https://github.com/ujh/iomrascalai/issues">Github issue tracker</a>, and
ask what do work on either in the
<a href="https://gitter.im/ujh/iomrascalai">chat</a> or in the
<a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/iomrascalai">Google Group</a>.</p>

<p>And if you&rsquo;re interested in artificial intelligence then this could be
interesting for you, too. After all, the goal is to write a program
that is good a playing this game!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducting Iomrascálaí]]></title>
    <link href="http://bettong.net/2014/04/29/introducting-iomrascalai/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-29T08:51:04+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://bettong.net/2014/04/29/introducting-iomrascalai</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>or <em>&ldquo;Help me learn Rust by pairing with me&rdquo;</em></p>

<p>After years working in interpreted languages (Ruby, JavaScript) I recently discovered <a href="http://www.rust-lang.org/">Rust</a>. As I sadly don&rsquo;t have the opportunity to use Rust directly in a client project, I decided to come up with a toy project to help me learn the language.</p>

<p>As Rust is supposedly good for programs that actually need raw speed (unlike the web apps I generally write) I decided to come back to one of my old time favourites: an artificial intelligence for the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Go_(game)">game of Go</a>.</p>

<p>I had already tried writing a few of those in recent years (including helping <a href="https://github.com/ujh/housebot">Jason House with his bot written in D</a>), but every time I had the problem that working alone wasn&rsquo;t very motivating so I never managed to produce a working program.</p>

<p>To combat this I&rsquo;m trying to pair program with people (i.e. <em>you</em>) to keep me going. So if you&rsquo;re interested in either learning Rust with me or writing an AI for the game of Go, <a href="mailto:contact@urbanhafner.com">please get in touch</a>!</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Currently (as of April 2014) the project is still in it&rsquo;s infancy (actually no code was written, yet), but please check out the <a href="https://github.com/ujh/iomrascalai">repository</a> and <a href="https://trello.com/b/NU4MXbao/iomrascalai">Trello board</a>.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re new to Rust I suggest the <a href="http://static.rust-lang.org/doc/master/intro.html">30-minute Introduction to Rust</a>, <a href="http://static.rust-lang.org/doc/master/tutorial.html">The Rust Language Tutorial</a>, and <a href="http://rustbyexample.com/">Rust by Example</a> as a start. If you&rsquo;re new to the game of Go &hellip; well there&rsquo;s <a href="http://senseis.xmp.net/">a whole Wiki about it</a>! And for computer go related content the best place is the <a href="http://dvandva.org/pipermail/computer-go/">computer-go mailing list</a>.</p>

<p><em>So, please get in touch so that we can get this started!</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
